Z Nation 이전 줄거리 건너뛰기
Previously on Z Nation
What the hell is going on?
The path to truth, it's
not a straight line.
[growling]
Long gestating plans have been percolating.
Coming into fruition all at once.
I am the true incarnation
of the resurrected.
Communication towers.
Multi-layered encryption.
All of the damn chem trails in the sky.
I mean have you seen that?
What is that?
Holy acid flashback man.
[guitar music plays]
♪
[electric zapping]
[unintelligible garbled sounds]
[guitar music plays]
♪
우린 이 도로를 벗어 나야 해요
We need to get off the road.
난 여기 좀비구역서 최대한
멀어지고 싶은거야
I don't like being so
far in Zero's territory.
그러나 우리가 다른 선택은 없는 가 봐
But I guess we really don't have a choice.
♪
♪ [electronic beeping]
[music stops and resumes]
Wait.
저게 뭐죠?
What is that?
♪
[growling]
새로운 건데
That is a new one.
난 저게 뭘 하는 지 보고 싶은데
Well I want whatever did that.
사무라이식 도축을 했는데
Like a Samurai surgeon.
이런건 정말로 획기적인 거인데
Some things you just can't unsee.
[gunshot]
4234번째군
Four thousand two hundred and thirty four.
그리고 오늘로써 3번째구
And a third.
그냥 보이는 대로 다 죽이는구먼
Take the whole kill. You deserve it, kid.
35번째
Thirty-five.
♪
[electronic beeping]
여기가 그 유명한 소를 도축을
하던 외계인 지역인걸 들어본 적이
[muffled] You know they used to
find mutilated cattle out here,
있는 사람 손 들어
back Pre Z.
외계인 소 도축이요?
[muffled] Mutilated cattle?
응 엑스파일서 안 봤어?
Like X-Files mutilated cattle?
맞아요 삼춘이 애길 한적이 있어요
외계인 출몰 지역이요
Yeah, my uncle knew all
about it. Aliens did it.
혹시 너 좀비 대마핀거 아냐?
Have you been smoking my Z weed?
No.
그럼 그거나 피고 임 좀 다물어
Well maybe you better start.
UFO를 믿지 않아?
You believe in UFOs?
[electronic beeping]
Sure.
말도 안되요 외계인은 없어요
That's ridiculous. Aliens don't exist.
만약 그들이 존재를 한다면
여기에서 그런 짓이나 하지 않겠지
If they were smart enough to
get here, they wouldn't put up
이런 멍청한 좀비들이나 도축하고 말야
with the dumb-ass human race for a minute.
그건 비과학적 논리야
It's pure science fiction.
그런데 좀비들이 있잖아요 그러니 외계인들도
That's what people said about zombies.
내 말은 좀비은 맞는데 그건 아닌 소리지
Well, I mean maybe there's zombies.
어이 그래도 좀비가 있는데 외계인들도 없지
But there sure as hell ain't no aliens.
[music stops]
[car engine stops]
오 제발 이 녀석아 시동 좀 걸려라
Come on, baby. Don't fail me now.
[unintelligible garbled sounds]
무슨 언어인거지?
What the hell kind of language is that?
외계인이 말 거는 것 같아요
Sounds like alien cross talk to me.
너 일부러 그런 말해서 내 기분 잡치게
할려고 하는 것 아냐?
Now you're just saying that
to piss me off, aren't you?
[unintelligible garbled sounds continue]
나만 여기서 기분이 오싹한건가요?
Am I the only one a little creeped out?
[unintelligible garbled sounds continue]
저 불빛이 어디서 나오는 잘 감시해?
Anybody have eyes on where
that light's coming from?
[unintelligible garbled sounds continue]
내 말이
Like I was saying.
[unintelligible garbled sounds continue]
[music resumes]
[car engine starts]
저거 흥미로운데
Well that was exciting.
난 내 종말보다 이게 더 신기한지 모르겠어
I don't want my apocalypse any
more exciting than it already is
thank you.
♪
누가 저기 앞서 가서 뭔지 보고 올 사람?
Somebody wanna go ahead
and tell me what that was?
비행기인가?
A plane?
저런 비행운을 본적이 있어
Been seeing those contrails for a while.
그냥 구름이라고?
Is that possible?
저건 분명 날라 다닌거야
Somebody flying something.
아 집중해
All right, listen.
울 아빠는 저런 게 있다고 하셨어
My dad was this no
bullshit, tell it like it is,
비행기 조종사였지
Air Force pilot.
아빠는 저런 비행 물체는 본적이 있고
He told this story about
seeing this brightly lit craft
네바다 북쪽에서 저런 현상을 목격하셨지
buzzing over him in northern Nevada.
그런 일이 있는 후 정말로 믿으셨지
And it made him a total believer.
그래서 난 아주 많은 걸 재잘되면서
물어보았죠
And even as a little
girl, I like I wondered.
더 이상 궁금하진 않네
Well wonder no more.
좀비는 확실히 있고
외계인은 없어
Zombies got here first.
There are no aliens.
내 말이
Well I dunno.
UFO는 늘 비행보다 바른 상태라고
사람들이 그랬지
A UFO seems more likely than
somebody still able to fly a jet
오늘 우리가 본 것은 맞는 것 같아
today. Especially one that can do that.
내 말이
I'm telling ya
널 물게 만들지
Don't make me bite you.
농담이야
Kidding.
[electric guitar theme music plays]
♪ Have mercy.♪
[gunshots]
♪ Oh, have mercy. ♪
그냥 만들어 봄 수정 배포 자유 -
하도 안 나와서 오립니다 그냥 즐감요^^
- Sync and corrected by TheDelta -
- www.addic7ed.com -
10K, 망원경 좀 가져와
10K, let me see your scope.
저기가 우리가 가기에 확실한가 보게
Let's see if there's something
for us to go believe in.
Okay, Addy. 난 우릴 따라오고
Okay, Addy. You can follow us in this
저쪽으로
Thing.
Thanks.
만약 우리가 도망가야 한다면
Just in case we need to make a getaway.
우리가 단박에 올라 타야 해
Looks like something crashed all right.
저게 만약 전투비행기라면 우릴 찾을꺼야
If it was a plane, we
should definitely find it
종말보다 무섭게 우릴 죽일꺼고
and fly it the hell out of this apocalypse.
저게 운전 보다 빠를 것 같아요
It's a lot faster than driving.
공교롭게도 내가 마지막에 비행길
잡았을 땐 그러질 못했지
No thanks. Last time I got in
a plane, it didn't end so well.
뭔가 문제가 있었나봐?
Does anything in your life?
그게 내가 본적이 없던 비행기
모습을 해서 말야
Yeah, well it didn't look
like any plane I've seen.
우린 로스웰에 도착했어
And we are in Rozwell.
좀비들과 같이 말야
With a Z.
머피 말이 맞아 어찌 됐던지
이것들은 지구 생명체가 아니지
Murphy's right. Whatever it
is, it isn't extraterrestrial.
이거 무슨 드론 같은 건가?
What, some kind of drone?
Maybe.
근데 뭔 종류의 드론인거아?
What kinda drone moves like that?
내가 말했잖아 우리 삼춘이
I'm telling ya, my uncle
입 다물라 했지
Don't say it.
이게 우리가 믿어야 하는 상황인거지?
Is this what I'm supposed to believe in?
외계인 불시착 뭐 이런것
Crash site of some kind.
꼭 미래와 같군
Looks like the future.
살펴보니 여기에 오랫동안 있던 모습이네
Well it's definitely been here a while.
모든 문제가 발생 했을 때
불시착한 것 같아
Probably crashed back
when everything went bad.
여기에 뭐라 표식이 되어 있는 것 같은데
Looks like there's some markings here.
좀 이상하고
Kinda weird.
이건 비행기가 아니예요 날개가 없어요
It's not a plane. There's no wings.
그럼 헬기 나 다른 건가
Helicopter or something.
그런데 헬기 회전 축이 안보여
Yeah, but where are the rotors?
이게 뭐죠?
Guys, what is it?
만약 UFO라 하며 난 나갈꺼야
If anyone says flying
saucer, I'm out of here.
이거 보이기가
Well it sure looks like a
원형 비행 실험체처럼 생겼어
An airborne disc of some kind.
이게 뭐든 어젯 밤 우리가
본 것 과는 다른 종류야
Well whatever it is, it's not
the thing we saw last night.
자 가자고 제발
So let's keep going.
로스웰 안으로?
Into Roswell?
우리 식량들 필요 하잖아
We need supplies.
대단해 좀비 외계인을 보겠군
Great, more alien huggers.
[growling]
외계인 따윈 상관없어 다 미신이야
Never mind aliens. Puppies
and kittens, people.
[growling]
[gunshot]
여기에 더 있어
Couple more over here.
10K, 너가 가
10K, you're up.
[growling]
[splorch]
4236과 4237번
Four thousand two hundred
thirty-six. Thirty-seven.
[growling]
3시 방향에
Three o'clock.
[growling]
[swish]
[splorch]
Four thousand two hundred thirty-eight.
이 녀석 대단해
Kid's on a roll.
여기가 그 유명한 엑스파일이 나온 곳이네요
Okay, talk about "I want to believe."
이게 유일하게 로스웰 시민들이
믿었던 미신인거지
The only thing the good
people of Roswell believe in
결국 다 돈벌이 인거야
is liberating money from suckers.
그 신봉자들이 안에 있는 것 같아요
Looks like we got some believers inside.
여기에 방문을 하러 오신 건가요?
Are you here for the Visitors?
방문이요?
Visitors?
내 생각에는 그자의 얘긴
I think he means
Bernadette를 만졌거나 보신게 아닌지?
Have you been touched by Bernadette?
뭐요?
Who?
걱정말아요. 전 Roy라고 해요.
전 오티 담당해요
Don't worry. I'm Roy. I'll
help you with the orientation.
오티요?
Orientation?
탈출을 위해서죠
Yeah. For the exodus.
뭔 탈출?
What exodus?
다 이해를 못하셔도 괜찮아요
새로운 식구들이 여길 오죠
It's okay to be confused.
Many new arrivals are.
리버사이드에서도 오고
아이오와에서도 오고
We had a guy from Riverside, Iowa show up,
그럼 이 자가 우주선의 선장인가요
thought he was a starship captain.
[laughing]
아니 지금 우리가 너의 그 병신 같은 이야길
Are we supposed to understand
이해 해줘야 하는 상황인가요?
what the hell you're talking about?
여기에 계시면 이해 할 수 없는
많은 일들이 생깁니다
You've been drawn here
by inexplicable visions
비행체의 오묘한 불꽃에서
기분이 좋아지잖아요?
of leaving the planet on
a chariot of fire, right?
아니요 우린 그 비행 물체에 대해
알아 보러 온거예요
No. We were drawn here by
inexplicable visions of finding
거기에다 음식과 기름이 있음 좋겠군요
food and gas.
당신들은 영생에 대한 생각을 가지고
오신 게 아닌가 보군요
You didn't have a dream of
a large elongated human form
대부분의 사람들은 로스웰에
영생을 위해 오니깐요
with almond eyes telepathically
urging you to come to Roswell
요즘 같은 시절엔 말이죠
at this appointed time?
Nope.
우리가 오는 길에 이상한 불빛을 보긴 했어요
We did see some really
strange lights in the sky
지난 밤에 말이죠
last night though.
아주 이상하더라고 뭐가 오싹하고
Everything's strange to
you. You grew up in a cave.
중요한 점은 아직 늦지 않으신 거란 거죠
Well the important thing
is that you're not too late.
Bernadette가 되돌아 오기 전에
주변을 소개해드리죠
Let me show you around
before Bernadette returns.
제가 여러분께 제 Xtronauts
친구들을 소개 하죠
I'll introduce you to
your fellow Xtronauts.
Xtronauts?
네 이들이 여러분들이 궁금해 하는
외계인들이예요
Hey, man. These... these
aliens that you're looking for,
신봉자가 아니예요
they're not the probing kind are they?
우린 그런 신봉자가 아니예요
그들은 미친거죠
No. We are not abductees.
Those people are crazy.
우리 신봉자이고 우리는 제발로
온 사람들이예요
We're inductees. We've
been invited, not kidnapped.
우리 자신을 Xtronauts라고 칭해요
We refer to ourselves as Xtronauts because
우리가 비행선을 타고 지구 곳곳이
다니는 첫 인간들이기 때문이죠
we will be the first humans
to explore the alien world.
그럼 그렇게 하고자 하는 계획은 뭔가요?
So, ummm. How do you plan
on doing that exactly?
종말로부터 도망 나온 방문자들 중에
The Visitors are coming to
save us from the apocalypse.
우리가 선별해서 뽑고선 우주선을
탈 수 있게 훈련을 하죠
We have been chosen,
and they're almost ready.
6일 후에 Bernadette가 누군 태울지
고릅니다
Just six more days. Bernadette
is in close contact with them.
Bernadette?
우리 모두 그것을 보았지요
We've all seen them.
그녀가 유일한 영매사예요
But she's the only one
they communicate with.
그럼 로이씨 다른 외계인들은
어떻게 대화를 하죠
And Roy, the... the aliens
that you communicate with,
그들이 무전기로 대화를 하나요?
do they by any chance use a radio?
무전기는 너무나도 신호가 약해요
Radio is far too primitive for them.
그들은 지구인의 기술은 필요 없답니다
They don't need our technology.
그들은 그녈 통해서 전달을 해요
They communicate with her telepathically.
드디어
Finally.
그들이 왔군요
They are here.
그들이 말해준 것처럼
상황이 생겼네요
It's happening just
like they said it would.
새로운 자들이 왔다고요
Strangers have arrived.
이쪽으로 오시면 다른 방문자들도
기다리고 있답니다
Among them will be the one
the Visitors are waiting for.
그들이 말하길
They said
그가 여기에 왔다고 하더라고요
And here he is.
사절단에 말이죠
The Emissary.
Oh, oh, okay.
[clapping]
[growling]
[gunshot]
Four thousand two hundred thirty-nine.
우린 여러분이 불고기 치킨을
좋아하실지 궁금하네요
We hope you like teriyaki chicken.
우리가 남은 게 이거라서요
It's all we have left.
No beef stroganoff?
감사하네요 잘 먹을께요
I'm sure it will be fine. Thank you.
얼마나 머피 사절단을 여기에
두실 껀가요?
How long we gonna let them think
that Murphy's their emissary?
우리가 저 사절단에 음식과 필수품을
줘야 할 때 가지죠
As long as they keep giving
the emissary food and water.
우리는 최대한 금방 가겠어요
We'll be out of here soon enough.
먼저 가세요 사절단 여러분
After you, your Emissary.
인간들의 정이 나쁘지만은 않지 응 머피??
Savior of the human race wasn't
good enough for you, huh Murphy?
가끔 외계인 대사도 필요하지
Needed to be the alien ambassador too.
내가 언제간 지구 정복자가 되서
다 엎어 버릴꺼여
I'm working my way up to
Supreme Leader of the Planet.
[clearing throat]
Can I help you?
Dan.
Dan Scully.
당신이 이 외계인 신봉자들을
다 믿지는 않을 것 같은데
And I bet you don't believe any
of this alien exodus crap either
아닌가요?
do you?
No, we don't.
맞아요 이자들은 다 미친거죠
Neither do I. These people are nuts.
그럼 뭐하시는 건가요?
So what are you doing here?
그냥 지나가다가 당신 얘길 듣고 온거요
Just passing through when
I came upon these folks.
그들이 말하길 외계인과
UFO를 보는게 사실이라 하고
They think they've been
actually seeing UFOs and this
Bernadette라 여자가 거기로 인도 한다고 들었소만
Bernadette chick has been talking to them.
누군가는 들 미친 사람이 있지 않겠소
Someone who knows better
근데 여기 모인 바보들은 외계인들이
자신을 구원할거라 믿으니 말이요
than to believe that UFOs
are coming to save us.
Right.
[laughing] Right.
그럼 여기 정확히 무슨 일이 이루어지는
지 아는 분은 또 없나요?
So you wanna know what's really going on?
Not really.
이 자 말을 듣지 마세요
Don't listen to him.
우리 또한 무슨 일이 이루어지는 모르지 않소.
Of course we want to know
what's really going on.
그 외계인들은 우릴 살려두지는 않는 것 같아요
The aliens are not coming to save us.
왜냐하면 이미 여기에 왔으니깐요
Because they're already here.
내 말이 이 병신 같은 상황이
뭔지 좀 알아 내라 했지
I told you we didn't want
to know what's going on.
그들은 수천년동안 여기에 이미 와 있었어요
They've been here for thousands of years.
그들이 그 좀비 바이러스를
퍼트린 자들이고요
They're the ones who
caused the zombie virus.
그들은 지구핵에서 살고,
지구 표면에서는 발견이 안되오
They live inside Pluto,
which isn't really a planet.
그러니 우주선 밖을 나오게 된다면
얼마나 끔찍 할껀가요
It's really a hollowed out spaceship.
이게 영양가 없는 정보인건 아시죠
Okay. You know this is
all very informative,
그리고 전 지구 태생이라서요
but I'm due back on planet Earth, so
오 알겠어요
Oh, I know.
내가 미쳤다고 생각하시는 건가요
You think I'm crazy.
Yeah, I do.
요즘 미친 세상엔 제정신이면 살 수나 있오
Well these days crazy stays alive.
내가 만약 당신 쪽 사람이라면
If I was you people,
여길 벗어 날꺼요
I'd get out of here
좀비 외계인이 날 집어 삼키기 전에 말이요
before the zombie aliens
come back and infect us all.
더 늦기 전에 벗어나요
Do it now before it's too late.
Doc.
당신이 뭘 원하던지
And whatever you do,
그 외계인 아줌마 말 듣지 마시오
do not listen to that Bernadette chick.
그녀가 당신들을 다 죽일껍니다
She will get you all killed.
좋아 미친자는 보호소로 들어가야지
그만 가세요
Okay. The lunatics have taken
over the asylum. Time to go.
그럼 우리가 본 물체는 뭐지?
What about that aircraft "thing" we saw?
그게 우릴 여기서 벗어나게 해주지 않는가
That can fly us out of here.
여기에 사실 공군기지가 있잖아요
There's an Air Force base here actually.
그들이 60년대에 버린 곳이 아닌가
They abandoned it back in the 60's.
그건 헛소문이고요
But that's just a cover story.
난 UFO가 차라리 나아
Well I want to believe in UFOs.
난 누군가 내 엉덩이에 외계인
좀비를 넣는 다면
I mean if somebody wants
to fly my ass off this
여기서 안전히 지내다가 그냥 가겠어
god forsaken planet, I'm cool with it.
Are you serious?
우리가 지금 이야길 하는 거는
Are we actually talking about
버려진 공군기지를 지금 여기
로스웰에서 가는 거잖아요
going to an abandoned
Air Force base in Roswell
차라리 우주선을 강탈해서 캘리포니아로
날라 가자는 얘기나 이거나 맞나요?
to see if we can find a
UFO to fly us to California?
너가 그렇게 얘길 한다면
Well when you say it like that
지금 말이 된다고 생각해?
You mean in English?
우리가 보긴 했잖아요
Look. We did see something.
무언가 비행을 했고요
And that something was flying,
그럼 거기에 물과 음식 기름이 있단 소리죠
which means there's a
ground crew with fuel, food,
연락이 끊긴 그 친구와 다시
연락을 할 수도 있고
and communication. And I want
to get a look at that base.
아마도 너 친구인 댄이 우릴 지구
핵(비행기지)로 데려다 준 것 같네여
Maybe your buddy Dan can
show us the way... to Pluto.
제가 보여줄게요
I can show you.
Oh my god.
저기에 얼마나 있었던거지?
How long have you been there?
한 동안요
A while.
근데 무섭진 않아 (무섭다는 표현)
Okay. That's not creepy.
제가 당신들을 거기로 안내 해드릴께요
여기서 멀지 않아요
I can show you where the
base is. It's not far.
제가 거길 언제나 가죠
거기서 그들과 교감을 나눠요
I go there all the time.
That's where they contact me.
The aliens?
그들은 방문자라고 불리우길 좋아해요
They prefer the term Visitors.
우리가 거기서 무전기와 비행길 찾을 꺼라고
Who knows, maybe we'll
find a plane and a radio.
아님 빅풋이나
Or bigfoot.
웃지마요 우리 삼춘이 빅풋에게
던져진적이 있어요
Hey, don't laugh. My
uncle had a Sasquatch pelt.
Come.
보여드릴께요
I'll show you.
이것들이 날 오싹하게 만드는 걸
(Addy) Those things are really
starting to freak me out.
난 이게 뭔지 알고도 싶지 않아
(Doc) I'd like to know
who and what is doing that.
전기톱도 보이는데
I've seen chain saws do that.
그런가
Sort of.
지구 물건이 아닌가봐
Yeah, that's not human
technology. Just saying.
말 멈추지마
Well stop just saying.
방문자들이 절 위해 그런 거예요
The Visitors did this.
They were protecting me.
♪
천천히 가요 이러다가 좀비랑
만나면 힘들어져요
Slow down, girlfriend. We don't
want to run into any zombies.
걱정마요 그들이 절 구해주니깐요
Don't worry. They won't
let anything happen to me.
당신이야 그렇지만 우린 어쩌라고
You don't happen to know if
that applies to us too, do you?
Wow.
무슨 외계인 기술 같은데
Look at this high tech alien technology.
Bernadette 여기에 무슨 무전기
같은 건 없나요?
Bernadette, you don't know
if there's any radio equipment
그들이 사용하는 건요?
around here that maybe
the Visitors may have used?
오래 된 배전실 같은게 있어
There's a room with old electrical stuff.
무전기가 있을 지도 몰라
There might be a radio in it.
어디에 있어요?
Yeah, where would that be?
당신 뒤에요
Right behind you.
무전기 확인 하자고
We'll check out the radio.
왜 다른 건 없을 꺼라고 생각해요
Why don't you guys see what else you find.
Be careful.
You too.
다른 건 없어?
What you got?
Nothing.
다 부서졌는데
This thing's stripped.
All right. Let's go.
Follow me.
[growling]
Look out!
[slice]
[growling]
Addy! Get Bernadette!
엄마에게로 오렴
Come to mama.
[splorch]
[thwap]
[growling]
[clank]
[stab]
[slice]
[splorch]
가실까요?
Shall we?
환…영해요
Wel... come
ET.
무전기 안 보여
(Warren) We didn't find a radio.
그냥 좀비 몇몇이야
(Addy) We did find some Zs though.
Surprise, surprise.
(Murphy) Surprise, surprise.
버려진 곳일뿐이야
(Vasquez) Rest of the place is gutted.
누군가 글씨체가 이쁜걸
Well somebody's got nice handwriting.
제가 했죠 그래야 오실 때 편리하니깐요
I did that. This is where
they're going to land.
도대체가 이 외계인이 뭐가 그리도 좋다고
What makes you so sure that these aliens
기다리는 거요?
are the good guys anyway?
냅둬 머피. 그들 일이야 우린 신경 안쓴다고
Leave her alone, Murphy. They won't save
everyone. Only the ones who've been called.
그들은 우릴 지켜보고 있어요
They've seen what we did to ourselves.
우리가 좀비들에게 해하질 않길 바래요
They don't want us doing it to them.
그러나 그들은 우리 인간들이
조금은 남길 바래요
But they believe there's still
hope for some of humanity.
인간성 존엄 근거로 미쳐버리면
You better hope they have
a higher opinion of humanity
내가 먼저 입을 짖어 주겠어
than I do.
여기가 비밀 기지인가요?
What about the top secret areas?
여기가 당신 최대한 와 본 곳 아닐까요
You know more about this
base than you're telling us,
맞죠?
don't you?
Bernadette,
여기에 숨겨진 다른 장소는
is there some kind of hidden base
없는 가요?
that you're not telling us about?
그들이 사절단을 데려 오라 시켰어요
They told me only to bring the Emissary.
Why?
모르죠 목소리가 시켰어요
I don't know. That's what the voices say.
The voices?
The voices. 전 불빛속에서 그들과 조우를 했죠
The voices. I hear them. In the light.
뭐라고 하던가요?
What do the voices say?
처음에는 잘 들리지 않았어요
I don't understand it when I first hear it.
그러나 나중에 뭐라고 하는지 이해가 되더라고요
Only later does it make sense.
I just know what they mean.
그들이 여기 보다 나은 곳으로
데려다 준다고 했어요
They want to take us
away to a better place.
곧 시간이 다가오고 있고요
They said it would be soon.
지금 그들이 고치는 중인데
금방 끝난다고요
They're making repairs, but
they'll be finished soon.
와 뭐라는거야
Wow, far out.
나한테 원하는게 뭐라했나요?
And what do they want with me?
아직 얘길 하지 않았어요
They didn't say.
아마도 당신 외계인의 백신일지도 몰라요
Maybe you're the alien cure too.
Great. Just great.
그럼 얼마동안 이들과 교신을 한거죠?
So how long have you been in
contact with these Visitors?
처음에는
At first,
남들처럼 하늘에서 불빛을 봤어요
I was like everyone else.
I saw the lights in the sky,
그들이 누군지 몰랐고요 어느 날
but I had no idea what they
were. And then one night,
제가 좀비에게 쫓기고 있을때
I was about to be killed by Zs.
전 죽는 줄 알았어요
I was ready to die.
그러자 빛이 저에게 오구선 구해준다고 했어요
And then the light came and it
spoke to me and protected me.
[unintelligible garbled sounds]
여기로 데려왔죠
They led me here.
그럼 목소리가 들리는 장소로 데려다 주겠어요?
Can you take us there, this
place where you hear the voices?
Yes.
이게 뭐여?
How in the hell?
All right. 좀 무서운데
All right. I'm a little freaked out.
All right, 뭐가 오는거지?
All right, what now?
We wait.
마법의 샘물이라도 찾은 거야 닥?
(Addy) [laughing] Hope
springs eternal, huh Doc?
Cigarettes, cigarettes,
cigarettes, gum, cigarettes.
껌 좀 씹어봐
Try the gum.
뭐 다른건 없어?
Anybody got any quarters?
[slam]
The gum is free.
요즘 같은 세상에는 뭐든지 꽁짜지
It's the apocalypse. Everything's free.
이상한걸
That's weird.
껌이나 뽑아요
Try the gum.
그래 어차피 몸에 해로운걸 안해야지
All right, well I'm trying to quit anyway.
Doc, no!
[groaning]
지진이다!
Earthquake!
[all screaming]
이거 엘레베이터인데!
No, it's an elevator! Look!
이럴 줄 알았지요!
You knew this was gonna happen!
다 함께 오길 원했구요!
You wanted to come along!
그녀 어찌 안전 밸트를 매고 있어?!
How come she has a seatbelt?!
[moaning]
도착 했네요
We're here.
이건 도대체가 뭔지 모를
What the hell kind of
숨겨진 엘리베이터가 이루어진 곳이지?
acid trip fun house elevator ride was that?
[slam]
내가 여길 오자고 안 했잖아
I guess we're not going back that way.
Well, kid.
너 삼춘이 말한 숨겨진 기지 이야긴 맞는 것 같아
Your uncle was right
about the secret base part.
말했잖아요 진실이라고요
I'm telling you, it's all true.
이걸 하길 원하는 거야?
We sure we want to do this?
그래 맞는 말이야 넘 위험해
He's got a point. It's not worth the risk.
일단 이 아래 있는게 뭔지
확인부터 하고선 파악을 해요
Tell me you don't want
to know what's down here.
이 밑에 뭔가 있다는 자체가 맘에 안 들어
I don't want to know what's down here.
그분들이예요 여기에 그들이 계셔요
It's them. Those are
the voices. They're here.
Bernadette!
괜찮아요 그들은 제가 누군지 알아요!
It's okay! They know me!
일단 준비를 하고선 잘해냅시다
Get ready for anything.
여기에 그분들이 계셔요 잘 될꺼예요
They're here. Just like they said.
너무 아름 답지 않은가요?
Aren't they beautiful?
[purring-like sound]
이게 뭐지 정말이지 할 말이
Well I'll be damned.
우리 아빠가 이야기 한대로
Just like my dad said.
[purring continues]
우릴 해치진 않아요
They won't hurt us.
Wait.
[purring]
무언가 잘못 되었어요!
Something's wrong!
[snarling]
[gunfire]
안되요 쏘지 마요!
No, don't shoot it!
[gunfire]
[gunshot]
그를 죽였어요!
You killed him!
뒤로 물러나! Stay back!
Stay back! Stay back!
우리가 뭘 죽인 줄도 모르겠어
I'm not sure what we killed.
[beeping]
[rapid beeping]
Get down!
[explosion]
다음 번에 구조 낙하산이라도
챙기도 다닐꺼야
Next apocalypse I'm
wearing a paper jumpsuit.
[faint beeping]
내가 확인 해볼께
I'll check it out.
[faint beeping]
뭐지?
What is it?
Zombie guts?
Alien blood?
이거 미치겠어
Your guys is as good as mine.
왜 그를 죽인 거죠?
Why did you kill him?
그게 우리 일이니깐요
Because that's what we do.
당신들은 그럴 권리가 없어요
You can't kill what's not alive.
그 말이 맞긴 해도
Yeah, he's right about that.
뭔지 모를 땐
Whatever that was,
좀비로 변하기 전에 다
죽이는게 나아요
it died and turned zombie
way before we got here.
여긴 안전하지 않아 그러니 나가자고
Come on. It's not safe here. Let's go.
이걸 한 번 봐야 할 것 같지 않아요
Hey, guys. You might want to see this.
Let's go.
[beeping]
Warren! 이걸 봐
Warren! Look at this.
공상과학드라마 같아
Now that's some syfy shit.
이거 작동을 하나?
It's interactive?
Way cool.
Alien?
Maybe.
Maybe not.
Wait a minute.
이거 유닉스 시스템이야
It's a Unix system. I know this.
Really?
아뇨 나 미술고 나왔거든요
No. I went to art school.
그럼 좀비 시민과 대화를
나눌 수 있는 건가?
Okay, well can you use
it to contact Citizen Z?
한 번 해보지
I can try.
저쪽에서 뭐가 나와도 바로 죽여
At the risk of alerting
whoever's on the other side.
닥은 머피랑 같이 있고
All right. Well Doc,
you stay here with Murphy
에비가 대화에 성공한 후 우린 나가는 거야
while Addy tries to make
contact. And let's go.
Roger that.
Wow.
여기서 밑을 다 볼 수 있겠어
You can see the whole base from here.
그래서 우리가 오늘 걸 다 본 모양이야
That's how they knew we were coming.
무언가 울기 빠져 나가길 원한 것 같아
Something sure wanted out of here.
지금은 버려둔 곳 같아
Seems empty now.
Wait.
Bernadette 아줌마는?
Where's Bernadette?
I'm here.
우리가 그들을 믿질 못하면
이렇게 되는 것이예요
This is what happens
when we don't trust them.
그들이 그런건가요?
Aliens did this?
선택이 폭이 없군
We left them no choice.
작동 돼?
That work?
[rapid clicking]
뭐라고 설명을 못하겠어요
Can't tell if it's out of
배터리 문제인지 다른게
ammo or batteries.
여기에 있는 괴물은 뭐고 우릴 다
죽일려고 하는건지
What do you think was in
there? That thing we killed?
그러니깐요
I hope so.
뭔가 일이 더 꼬이는 것 같아
Cuz if it's something worse than that,
알고 싶지 않고
I don't want to find out.
What?
Okay.
Oh.
무언가 우릴 밖으로 보내는 것 같아
Something for you to look forward to.
그게 진짜지 허상인 모르겠어요
Yeah, I can't tell what's
real and what isn't.
먼가 이상하긴 해
Don't you think it's unusual
그들이 영어를 쓰는 것도 이상하고
that these aliens mostly
communicate in English. Mostly.
이미 우리 인터넷으로 공부라도 한건가
I dunno. Maybe this is their
tap into our old internet.
세계를 다닌 자료가 있어
They've got global files here.
Oh.
무슨 우주서 온 스토커와도 같아
Okay. So these aliens
are stalkers from space.
이거
Is that
미치겠군
Wow. I look like hell.
더 이상 없는데 뭐가
Well look what the cat dragged in.
그게 다야?
What is all this?
넌 스타군
You are one popular dude.
그건 뭐지?
And what's this?
Zona. Zona가 뭐야?
Zona. What's Zona?
그들 고향이 아닌가
Maybe it's their home planet.
아님 그들이 우릴 죽이러 들 때
필요한게 아니었을까
Or what they call the pie
they're gonna bake us into.
이쪽으로
This way.
[growling]
저기에 뭔가가 있어
There it is.
혹시 모르니 준비하고
Be ready for anything.
걱정마요 그들은 평화를 위해 왔어요
No, don't worry. They won't
hurt us. They come in peace. See.
이들이 원하는 걸 어찌 알아요?
What do you think it wants?
만약 좀비라면 우리 뇌를 먹을 꺼예요
If it's a zombie, it wants brains.
외계인이라면 문제인거고
If it's an alien, it wants to probe us.
난 어떤 일이 생기든 다 죽일거예요
Either way, I'm killing it.
죽이지 말아요
No! Don't kill it.
우릴 해치지 않아요?
Can't you see it doesn't want to hurt us?
[purring]
Bernadette, no!
괜찮아요
It's all right.
문제가 없어요
[whispering] It's okay.
[growling]
[gunshot]
- [growling]
- [gunfire]
쏘지 말아요
Please stop shooting him.
- [growling]
- [gunfire]
[muffled sound]
[gunshot]
[purring]
[beeping]
Bernadette!
Get down!
[explosion]
Bernadette!
쫒아가요
After them.
Bernadette!
죽이네
Sweet.
작동해?
Does it work?
글쎄요
I dunno.
[gun energizing]
[zapping-splorch]
되는 것 같아요
Guess that'd be a yes.
Four thousand two hundred forty-three.
[screaming]
Bernadette?
Come on. 그걸 가져와요
Come on. Bring that thing.
Ready?
What the hell?
다시 제자리야
We're right back where we started.
이게 무슨 마법인가?
What was Mr. Toad's Wild Ride for?
방문객 입장
Visitor's entrance.
그녀와 외계인은 안보여?
Anybody got eyes on
Bernadette or the alien?
There.
미치겠어
Well I'll be damned.
Careful, gentlemen.
일 그르치지마요
Don't get sucked up.
모든 건물이 살아있는 것 같아
Looks like the entire base is alive.
알겠어요
Not just the base,
모든 세상이 그런게지
the whole city.
우리가 뭘 찾은지 믿기가 힘들꺼예요
(Addy) You guys will not
believe what we found out on that
뭔데?
What is that?
이게 뭐야
I don't believe it.
Murphy,괜찮아?
Murphy, you all right?
Murphy?
Murphy, 안돼!
Murphy, don't!
[zapping]
10K,그들을 없애버려!
10K, don't let them get him!
[gun energizing]
[whoosh]
[zapping]
Murphy, don't do it! Don't go!
그들이 좋은 일로 데려가는게 아니야
They're gonna probe you for
sure! And not in a good way!
[gun energizing]
[whoosh]
Let's go. This way. 여기로 와
Let's go. This way. This way.
[explosion]
저게 터지질 않았으면 싶네요
Be careful that thing doesn't blow.
저게 살아있나요?
Is it alive?
뭐라 할 말이 없어
I can't tell.
Help him. 그를 도와줘요
Help him. Please help him.
Oh, oh god.
우리가 숨쉬어도 되는 건가요?
What if it can't breathe our air?
아무래도 다른 별에서 온 것 같아
Then I guess he came to the wrong planet.
[hissing of air]
[coughing]
김수현 (댄 스컬리)?
Dan Scully?
지구 핵서 온 자?
That nutjob from Pluto?
이해가 안되요, Mr. Scully.
I don't understand, Mr. Scully.
왜 외계인 흉내 내신거죠?
Why are you acting like one of the aliens?
미안해요 외게인은 없어요
I'm sorry, Bernadette. There are no aliens.
그게
It's
그게 저였어요
It was always just me.
속여서 미안해요
I'm sorry I lied to you.
비행선에 올라 타면 당신에게
말해 주고 싶었어요
I was gonna tell you the
truth once you got on board.
외계인들이 없다고?
You mean there are no aliens?
Only you?
Just me.
나머지들은
The rest were just
테스트 좀비 파일럿 이예요
test pilot zombies from year one.
어찌 살아 남으거예요?
Why are you still alive?
전 몇 달만 여기에 있었어요
I've only been here a few months.
대부분 죽었거나
Everyone was
좀비가 되었죠
dead or turned when I got here.
My job
여기서 기술 보완을 하던 사람이예요
was to salvage any technology
they were testing here.
난 파일럿이 되었어야만 하죠
I was supposed to fly
조나라고 불리던 프로젝트죠
this craft back to Zona.
And
당신과 함께 떠나고 싶었어요
I wanted to take you with me.
Zona가 어딘가요?
Where's Zona?
날 데려 가고 싶었다고요?
You wanted to take me?
정말 아름다워요
It's beautiful there.
그들이 어떻게 절 아나요?
How did they know about me?
얼굴 인식 프로그램이요
Face recognition software.
드론이 당신을 콜로라도에서부터
알았어요
A drone picked you up in Colorado.
A drone in Colorado?
이게 외계인 기술이네?
This is alien technology, isn't it?
누가 알겠어
Who knows.
그게 제 최선이었어요
That's all above my pay grade.
Oh wow.
난 안 할꺼야?
I'm not gonna make it, am I?
왜 저에게 얘길 하지 않았어요?
Why didn't you just tell me?
Because
그냥 사실을 말하면 떠날까봐 두려웠어요
I was... I was afraid you
wouldn't go without the others.
[moaning]
Dan?
그를 그만 보내주자고
Come on. Let's give him mercy. Come on.
[snarling]
[gunshot]
Come on.
[whispering] Come on.
[beeping]
[rapid beeping]
[explosion]
Told ya so.
암것도 없잖아
This proves nothing.
제대로 못 알아서 미안허이
I'm sorry it didn't work out.
난 외계인과 함께 가고 싶었어
You know I would've liked
to go with the aliens.
이놈의 세상이 뭔지
Anything to get out of
this damn apocalypse.
괜찮아요?
You going to be okay?
이게 제 모습이 아니라서
It's not me I'm worried about.
로스웰다운 거죠 뭐
It's all the others back at Roswell
그런 헛된 희망이라도 있어야 버티죠
who have all their hopes tied up on this.
저에게는요
In me
그럼 뭘 해야 하지?
What are you going to do?
I don't know.
난 믿어요
I believe in you.
She's here! She's okay!
우린 불빛과 폭발을 보고선
당신을 걱정했어요
We saw the lights and the
explosion. We were worried sick.
그들을 보았나요 뭐라고 해요?
Did you see the Visitors?
What did they say?
우리가 좀 더 기다리라고 해요
They said we need to wait longer.
우리 인간은 아직 나약하다고요
The human race isn't ready yet.